<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on ioctl.uk</title><link>/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on ioctl.uk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 09:12:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sensible Development with a Raspberry Pi 3</title><link>/2020/05/sensible-development-with-a-raspberry-pi-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 09:12:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>/2020/05/sensible-development-with-a-raspberry-pi-3/</guid><description>The Raspberry Pi 3 is surprisingly powerful. Here&amp;rsquo;s what mine does:
File serving using Samba. Git repository hosting using gitea. Continuous testing and building using Drone. Encrypted backups of itself and other hosts using duplicity Monitoring of my network: I dump various stats to rrd then plot via a small Go web renderer. Raspberry Pi 3 has two weaknesses for this set up: storage and 100Mbps network.
My Raspberry Pi 3 only uses its SD card to boot; all storage is on a separate NAS.</description></item><item><title>Dead Simple Linux Sandboxes</title><link>/2020/03/dead-simple-linux-sandboxes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 22:06:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/03/dead-simple-linux-sandboxes/</guid><description>bubblewrap is a wonderful tool for creating sandboxes as an unprivileged user. Here&amp;rsquo;s some useful sandboxes that I regularly use.
Reading Mail in Isolation #!/bin/sh exec bwrap --unshare-user --unshare-ipc --unshare-pid --unshare-uts --unshare-cgroup \ --ro-bind /bin /bin \ --ro-bind /lib /lib \ --ro-bind /lib64 /lib64 \ --ro-bind /usr/bin /usr/bin \ --ro-bind /usr/lib /usr/lib \ --ro-bind /usr/share/terminfo /usr/share/terminfo \ --ro-bind /etc/passwd /etc/passwd \ --ro-bind $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Build a new Linux Kernel under Debian</title><link>/2019/04/build-a-new-linux-kernel-under-debian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 19:21:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>/2019/04/build-a-new-linux-kernel-under-debian/</guid><description>This page describes how to build your own Linux kernel under Debian . It is often useful to build your own kernel as sometimes the Debian default lacks something you need (for example, I need to enable RMI4 on my Thinkpad X1C6) or includes bloat you do not want (e.g., uncommon protocols such as RDS that might leave you exposed to an undisclosed or future vulnerability unecessarily.
The official documentation for this is here provided by Debian here.</description></item></channel></rss>